## Kirill Ilyukhin

# Full Stack Software Developer

E-mail kilyukhin@gmail.com Phone +81-80-3418-9482 **LinkedIn** linkedin.com/in/kilyukhin **Github** github.com/kilyukhin

IT professional with 25 years of experience, involved in complete SDLC including analysis, design, development, testing, implementation, support and maintenance of enterprise-level and business critical systems using Java/JavaEE technologies on server side and iOS/Android/web/ native applications on client side. Experience in building high performance, fault tolerant and high availability systems.

Vast knowledge of financial products and investment banking

Highly motivated team player with the ability to work independently and adapt quickly to new and emerging technologies.

## **Technical Expertise**

Business Areas: Finance, Fixed Income Instruments, Algo Trading, Market data, Banking, Mobile Networks.

Programming Languages: Java, Swift, Objective-C, Javascript, TypeScript, SQL, Perl, Shell.

Data transfer: HTTP, HTTP long poll, WebSocket, Server-sent events.

Web technologies: HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, SASS, Ajax.

Other: Tomcat, Spring, Reactive Programming, Hazelcast, PostgreSQL, Sybase, Apache HTTP server, NginX, Git, Gitlab, Jenkins, Tibco RV, IntelliJ YouTrack/Upsource, AWS.

## **Professional Experience**

#### 2022-05 – Algo Developer at Morgan Stanley Japan, Tokyo, Japan

present Develop and maintain a range of business critical products for Fixed Income Division: market making, auto pricing, auto quoting, price contribution, handling of RFQs and RFMs for bonds, futures and swaps. Implement risk management and compliance controls. Work in a global team, across different regions and timezones.

## 2022-02 – Java Developer at TS IMAGINE Japan K.K., Tokyo, Japan

2022-05 Work on global financial solution for hedge funds, large asset managers, mutual funds, and brokers.

## 2005-10 - Software Consultant at Orchid Technology K.K., Tokyo, Japan

Develop, deploy and maintain a range of professional level products for delivery and presentation of real-time market data. Major products:

- StockWeather Real-time Stocks mobile app to access real-time Japanese market data. sc.mufg mobile app for Mitsubishi UFG Morgan Stanley. 取引所 3 6 5 mobile app for
  - Tokyo Financial Exchange. Responsible for server application (Java EE, Tomcat, PostgreSQL, Hazelcast, etc), iOS apps (Swift, Objective-C, UIKit, StoreKit, push notifications, etc) and Android apps
- NX-Web web service for JIJI Press Ltd. Enterprise service which delivers a powerful mix of real-time stock and other market data, company news, reports, quote lists, stock search, portfolio, etc. Provides essential news coverage for Japanese markets, along with comprehensive market data including stocks, FX rates, commodity prices and key global financial data. Responsible both for server applications (Java EE, Tomcat, SQL, Hazelcast, Tibco RV, Apache HTTP server, etc) and web applications (TypeScript, JavaScript, require.js, jQuery, backbone.js, CSS, SASS, etc).

- 2003-07 Senior Software Developer, Team Leader at Mera NN, Nizhny Novgorod, Russia
- 2005-10 Lead a team of developers working on Operation and Maintenance Center (Radio part), cellular network management software for Nortel Telecom. Added new features, fixed bugs and provided all kinds of support for 16 Megabyte C/C++/Java codebase.
- 1999-10 System Engineer at Sberbank of Russia, Ulyanovsk, Russia
- 2003-07 IT engineer of the department which handled all bank transactions of the region. Managed the department security: secure LAN segment, secure connections with local branches and upstream office, crypto keys, reliability of server grid and specialized hardware and software. Managed system for bills of exchange handling. Provided IT support for local branches.

Created a few utilities for local usage.

Half a year worked as a communication engineer, managing all ethernet cabling, phone wires and radio channels in the bank office.

- 1998-01 System Engineer / Software Developer at Federal Service for Supervision of Transport,
- 1999-10 Ulyanovsk, Russia

Built and managed LAN of the organization. Maintained all kinds of hardware. Created some software utilities for local usage.

#### Education

- $1993\text{-}09- \quad \textbf{MS in Applied Mathematics, Computer Science}$
- 1998-06 Ulyanovsk State University, Ulyanovsk, Russia